solodsergey287@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/sergeisolod https://sergeisolod.github.io

SUMMARY

Experienced Middle Frontend developer (4 and a half years full time) with deep understanding of developing complex projects in product startups (Scrum methodology). I've developed about 20 commercial projects (SEO friendly) from idea to release, which are used by thousands of people, remade many projects from legacy technologies to new ones. Expert level of JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, CSS and other technologies. Ready for test tasks or trial day.

Skills

Technical: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, CSS3, HTML5, Saas, Jest, NextJS, VueJS, Webpack, Babel.js, Gulp, REST APIs, WebSocket, ESLint, MaterialUI, jQuery, Bootstrap, AJAX, Git, Terminal macOS/Linux.

Other: Jira, Figma, Zeplin, Scrum, Agile, SEO, UI, UX, Wordpress, Joomla, Wix, Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager.

Experience

Digift Gift Cards

Remote (Thessaloniki, Greece)

Middle Frontend Developer

Feb 2020 - Present (3 years 5 months)

- I've developed about 20 complex projects (admin panels, online stores, widgets, payment systems, etc.) from idea to production in a large team using the Scrum methodology. These projects are used by tens of thousands of people and bring hundreds of thousands of dollars.
- I've remade 5 large old projects from legacy technologies (PHP 5, Vue 1, jQuery) to new ones (TypeScript, React, Redux), which reduced the time of implementing features and saved thousands of hours of development.
- Supported all projects, including legacy code, fixed bugs, implemented features, improved existing projects, regularly reviewed the code, which allowed to increase sales and improve reputation.
- I was fully responsible for most of the projects, participated in the architectural development. Many fundamental
 decisions were made by me, such as the choice of technologies, programming language, architecture, which made
 it possible to use the latest technology and best practice.
- I trained and mentored the employees and also made training videos for colleagues, clients and developers. This allowed new employees to fit in the team and bring value.
- I've made SEO optimization of our projects on React (NextJS, NodeJS), which allowed them to appear frequently
 in search results and attract more clients.
- I've developed new complex and modern animations for all projects, created a gift envelope with unusual json animation, which improved the user experience and increased gift card sales.
- I've developed many different and complex email letters, implemented WebSocket payment processor and authorization with a token, where it was needed.
- I've implemented features into projects that improve user experience: email autocomplete, input masks, croppers, clear validation, displaying errors and hints, etc.
- My projects had min 85% test coverage (Jest), which allowed me to reduce the number of bugs by finding them quickly, make the project stable.

Foodle

On-site (St Petersburg City, Russia)

Junior Frontend Developer

Feb 2019 - Jan 2020 (1 year)

- I've developed a project (React, Redux) that helps to see restaurant menus and order food (main business idea), which allowed to increase revenue and occupy the market.
- As a part of the team I participated in the development of the future project architecture. I suggested ideas that were implemented and reduced the load on the server, increased the productivity of the project.
- I've fixed bugs, implemented a lot of features, which improved reputation and increased the number of clients.

Freelance

Remote (St Petersburg City, Russia) May 2018 - Jan 2019 (9 months)

Frontend Developer

- I've developed many websites for my clients, which allowed them to be represented on the Internet, sell services, increase revenue and sales, improve reputation.
- I supported my clients' sites, fixed errors and bugs, introduced new features, I also supported the CMS platforms WordPress, Wix, Joomla. This increased the sales and improved the attitude of users towards the product.
- I implemented in the site code GA, GTM and client required libraries. This allowed my clients to see statistics, work comfortably, find their weaknesses and increase sales.

Educational

Saint Petersburg State University